# Gitonga Amos Mugendi

Nairobi Kenya

+254793805246

amosmugendii07@gmail.com

Experienced Web Developer with a strong background in HTML, CSS, PHP, and Python. Skilled in developing, maintaining, and troubleshooting web applications. Demonstrated ability to excel independently and as part of a team. Known for optimizing systems and implementing technical solutions to improve operational efficiency and user experience.

### Skills

PHP development Back end development

Code optimization Object-oriented programming

HTML and CSS Python programming
Continuous deployment Continuous integration

Data structures RESTful APIS
Software documentation Software testing

# **Work History**

#### **Junior Software Developer**

Renga Technologies, Nairobi, Kenya.

September 2024 - Current

- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Designed customized solutions for proposals to potential customers.
- Translated customer requirements into written use cases.
- Participated in software field testing to verify performance of developed projects.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Estimated work hours and tracked progress using Scrum methodology.
- Built databases and table structures for web applications.

#### Freelance developer

Nerdy Turtles, Remote

January 2023 - January 2024

- Developed and implemented web applications using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to ensure a visually appealing, secure, and intuitive user experience for clients
- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Translated customer requirements into written use cases.

#### IT assistant

Rafiki Bank, Nairobi, Kenya

May 2022 - August 2023

- Installed and maintained software applications, optimized existing systems and databases, and mitigated security threats across all network devices
- Improved network security by deploying an automated alert system, achieved an average of 95% detection rate of malicious activities, reduced downtime by 40%, and improved the organization's resilience to security threats by 25%
- Responded to queries on phone, via email or through IT ticketing system.
- Maintained current software licenses and patched applications to stay up-to-date with latest features.

Upwork, Nairobi, Kenya

 Developed and maintained websites using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, with a focus on improving performance using modern web development techniques and best practices

#### IT assistant

IEBC Kenya, Nairobi, Kenya

August 2022 - September 2022

- Maintained current software licenses and patched applications to stay up-to-date with latest features.
- Utilized advanced troubleshooting methodologies to successfully troubleshoot IT related issues and reduce downtime of organization's systems, resulting in 20% decrease in resolution times for reported issues
- Implemented automation scripts to automate manual tasks, enabling faster resolution of user queries

•

## Education

Moringa School at Nairobi, Kenya

Certification in Software Engineering November 2024

Catholic University of Eastern Africa at Nairobi, Kenya., Kenya Bachelor of Science in Computer science October 2023

Nyeri High School at Nyeri, Kenya., Kenya **High School Diploma** November 2018

# **Certifications**

- HTML and CSS Certification Course, Udemy, 2022
- Certified in HTML, CSS, and Java script for web development

### References

- Dr. Paul Mwenda, Senior Consultant, Sparrow Solutions Ltd, 0721819319
- Collins Kipruto, Senior Software Engineering Renga Technologies, 0722545735
- Njaramba Kanani, Head of Security, Rafiki Microfinance, 0720702465

# Languages

English